靠  我的维萨卡被撤了
Oh, damn, they canceled my Visa.
哦也  新的万事达卡
Oh, yay, a new MasterCard!
干嘛
What?
我本来想拿信件
I was going to get my mail.
拿啊
Okay.
难道你想通过心灵感应来拿吗
Are... are you hoping to get it telepathically?
你是说意念取物吧
I think you mean telekinetically.
不是
And no.
我只是不确定用哪种社交礼节
I just wasn't sure of the proper protocol
因为你和莱纳德如今不交媾了
now that you and Leonard are no longer having coitus.
老天  你就不能说"不再见面交往"吗
God, can we please just say "no longer seeing each other"?
那得真的不见才行
Well, we could if it were true.
可你们住在同一栋楼里  低头不见抬头见
But as you live in the same building, you see each other all the time.
唯一改变的变量是交媾
The variable which has changed is the coitus.
咱来定个协议 你我继续做朋友 还有你别再说"交媾"
Okay, here's the protocol: you and I are still friends, and you stop saying "coitus."
好啊
Good, good.
我很高兴我们还是朋友
I'm glad we're still friends.
真的吗
Really?
当然  适应你出现在我日常生活中 可花了我不少功夫
Oh, yes. It was a lot of work to accommodate you in my life.
而我很讨厌白费功夫
I'd hate for that effort to have been in vain.
好吧
Right.
再问清楚  我不能跟所有人说交媾 还是只是不能跟你说
Just to be clear, do I have to stop saying "coitus" with everyone or just you?
所有人
Everyone.
协议条款真苛刻
Harsh terms.
不过没关系  我可以用"性交"代替
But all right-- I'll just substitute "intercourse."
这下好了
Great.
或者用"私通"
Or "fornication."
但这个带有批评色彩 还是作为备用吧
Yeah. But that has judgmental overtones, so I'll hold that in reserve.
你最近怎样
So, how you been?
我的存在是个连续统一体
Well, my existence is a continuum,
所以在指定期间的每个时间点都是一样的
so I've been what I am at each point in the implied time period.
你就是逗我玩  是吧
You're just coitusing with me, aren't you?
逗你玩
Bazinga.
莱纳德好吗
How's Leonard doing?
他表面很好
He seems all right.
但他花了很长时间
Although he does spend a disturbing amount of time
盯着你的照片
looking at photographs of you
嗅着你枕过的枕头
and smelling the pillow you slept on.
我想起来了
Oh, but now that I think of it,
他叫我不要告诉你
he asked me not to tell you that.
我会假装没听见
I'll pretend I didn't hear it.
我宁愿你假装我没说过
I'd rather you pretend I didn't say it.
你买了意大利妈妈大蒜意粉酱
I see you bought Mama Italia marinara spaghetti sauce.
对
Yep.
我妈妈也用这种酱
That's the sauce my mother uses.
她喜欢意式烹饪
She likes cooking Italian because according to her,
她说罗马人也这么做给耶稣吃
that's what the Romans made Jesus eat.
有意思
Interesting.
我改天晚上叫你过来吃
I'll have to have you over for spaghetti some night.
我现在就饿了
I'm hungry now.
好吧
Oh. Um, okay.
那一小时后过来吧
Why don't you give me an hour and come over?
能不能切点热狗丁 加到酱汁里
Will you cut up hot dogs into little chunks and mix them in with the sauce?
我没有热狗
I don't have hot dogs.
没关系  我有
Oh, it's all right; I do.
你就要做我妈妈所说的"美意大餐"
Oh! You're in for what my mother calls "a real Eye-talian treat".
你去哪了
Hey, where you been?
我刚刚和佩妮聊天呢
I was talking with Penny.
你怎么能这样
What's wrong with you?
你不能和室友的前任一起玩
You can't hang out with your roommate's ex.
这未免太逊了
That's totally uncool.
没关系  我不在乎
No, it's fine. I don't care.
我已经走出来了
I'm over it.
对  走出来了  所以他整天都在怨念
Yeah, he's over it; that's why he's been whining all day
要发明《黑超战警》里的洗脑装置
about trying to invent that memory-wiper gizmo from Men in Black.
他有进展了吗
Is he making any progress?
因为我想忘掉本·阿弗莱克居然演过《超胆侠》
Because I'd like to erase Ben Affleck as Daredevil.
本·阿弗莱克也会想洗脑的
So would Ben Affleck.
重点是  面对这种情况 你得做出选择
The point is, in a situation like this you got to pick sides.
要么选莱纳德队  要么选择佩妮队
You're either on Team Leonard or Team Penny.
哪个是选剩下的
Which one picks last?
什么
What?
我通常都只能在选剩下的那队
Well, usually I'm on the team that picks last.
除非有坐轮椅的孩子一起玩
Unless there's a kid in a wheelchair.
谢尔顿  我给你买了陈皮鸡丁
Sheldon, I got you your tangerine chicken.
你应该饿了吧
I hope you're hungry.
我当然饿了
Well, of course I'm hungry.
而且我没打算跟别的队吃饭
And as I have no plans to eat with any other team,
我会津津有味地 吃光陈皮鸡丁
I will consume my tangerine chicken with the appropriate gusto.
好吧
Okay.
只是出于好奇  我们还有热狗吗
Just out of curiosity, do we still have hot dogs?
不知道  怎么了
I don't know. Why?
吃饭时随便聊聊而已
Just making dinner conversation.
加油  小莱队
Go, Team Leonard!
生活大爆炸第三季第二十集
啊  太好吃了
Oh, God, this is good.
我问你个问题
Let me ask you a question.
你觉得你会因为
Do you believe you're going to go to hell
吃糖醋排骨而下地狱吗
for eating sweet and sour pork?
犹太人不相信有地狱
Jews don't have hell.
我们相信有胃酸倒流
We have acid reflux.
你要吃最后一只饺子吗  谢尔顿
Do you want the last dumpling, Sheldon?
当然
Certainly.
我又没有因为很快要吃第二餐
It's not like I have to moderate my food intake
而故意限制食物摄入量
because I'm planning on eating again very shortly.
大家今晚想玩什么
So, you guys want to do something tonight?
我不行 我要去水中有氧运动班接我妈
Nah, I can't. I got to pick up my mom from her water aerobics class.
十八个超重妇女在游泳池里 甩着肥大的手臂
18 overweight women flapping their arm fat in a swimming pool.
就像海洋世界里的海牛
Looks like the manatee tank at Sea World.
你呢  拉杰
What about you, Raj?
这算什么
Oh, there it is:
你没有女朋友了
now that you don't have a girlfriend,
就又想跟我玩了
you want to hang out with me again.
-我什么时候没跟你玩了  -少来了
- I never stopped hanging out with you. - Oh, please,
大家都清楚你没有人了 才会来找我
we all know I'm the friend you call when you have no other options.
如果我们是正义联盟  我就是海王子
If we were the Justice League, I'd be Aquaman.
我倒希望你是海王子
I wish you were Aquaman.
我就能派你去老人池里把我妈舀出来
Then I could send you to scoop my mom out of the old lady tank.
抱歉  我渴了  我要去冰箱里
Excuse me, I'm thirsty, so I'm going to go to the refrigerator
拿点清凉饮料喝
and get myself a refreshing beverage.
算了  我今晚就一个人过吧
You know what? I'll just spend the evening alone.
怎么  我突然就不配陪你了
What, suddenly I'm not good enough for you?
我最爱饮料了
I do so love beverages.
我现在要去饭后散步了
Now I think I'll take my after-dinner walk.
你什么时候开始饭后散步了
Since when do you take after-dinner walks?
你什么时候开始散步了
Yeah, since when do you take walks?
我在网上看过一篇论文  饭后百步走
I read a study online that walking after a meal
不仅有助于消化  还能增加5-羟色胺的含量
not only aids in digestion, but increases serotonin,
（一种有利于神经细胞间冲动传导的有机物）
而且你们也知道的  如果说相比提神饮料
and you know me, if there's one thing I like
我更喜欢什么  那肯定就是5-羟色胺了  拜拜
more than a refreshing beverage, it's serotonin. Bye-bye.
等等  我和你一起走
Hold on. I'll walk down with you.
没那个必要吧
That's not necessary.
你先走吧
You can go first.
要么咱俩一起走
Or we could go together.
我想不出什么理由拒绝你
I can't think of a reason why not.
咱们走吧
Let's go.
等一下
Hold on.
没事  我还是想不出什么理由
Nope, no reason.
我好想你
I've missed you.
行了  代我向你妈妈问好
All right, say hello to your mother for me.
行啊
Okay.
干嘛
What?
你刚说你要去散步的
You said you were going for a walk.
我又没说要去外面散步
I didn't say outside.
然后呢  你就打算来来回回地跑楼梯吗
So what, you're just gonna walk up and down the stairs?
不会  当然不会
No, of course not.
那样的话就太可疑了
That would be odd and suspicious behavior.
到这儿来  拉塞尔  过来呀  宝贝儿
Here, Russell! Here, boy!
你往哪边走
Which way are you going?
"你" 往哪边走
Which way are "you" going?
我把摩托车停在街那边了
I parked my scooter down the block.
我走另一边  拜拜
I'm going the other way. Bye.
拜拜
Bye.
其实是停在这边
Actually, I'm this way.
这是热狗的味道吗
Do I smell hot dogs?
不是  我是说  我不知道你闻到了什么
No. I mean, I have no idea what you smell.
我绝对闻到了生热狗的味道
I definitely smell raw hot dog.
估计是你的脑子里有肿瘤吧
Perhaps you're getting a brain tumor.
好了  散步愉快
All right, have a nice walk.
我会的  祝你开车愉快
I shall. Have a nice scoot.
你最好站开点儿
You might want to stand back.
寡人的坐骑有13马力呢
I'm sitting on top of 13 horses here.
你好啊  狗狗
Oh. Hello, doggie.
乖狗狗
Nice doggie.
估计你是闻到热狗的香味了
I bet you think you smell hot dogs.
看  有猫咪
Look, a cat!
佩妮
Penny?
Penny.
佩妮
给
Here.
剩下的热狗被我拿去保命了
I had to trade the others for my life.
喂  莱纳德
Hey, Leonard?
怎么了
Yeah?
我有一年没做爱了
I haven't had sex in a year.
你想干嘛  拉杰
Where you going with this, Raj?
别自作多情了  老兄
Don't flatter yourself, dude.
我想出去找个女人
I want to go out and meet a woman.
那就去呗  -我要找个帮手
- So, go.  - Well, I need a wingman.
我不想让自己看着像个失败的剩男
I don't want to come off like a lonely loser.
你觉得我跟你去你就不剩了吗
And you think "my" presence will help with that?
对呀
Well, I do.
有你在旁边  我有更有把握了
Next to you, I'll look like a catch.
我今晚不会出去的  拉杰
I'm not going out tonight, Raj.
好吧
All right.
你介意我到你房间去
Would you mind if I went to your room
下载几部亚系A片看吗
and downloaded some Asian pornography?
非常介意
Very much.
我可以不看亚系的
Doesn't have to be Asian.
别担心  总有一天你会遇见一个好姑娘的
Don't worry. You'll meet a girl someday.
-不可能的  -绝对可能  而且还很漂亮
- No, I won't.  - Yes, you will, and she'll be beautiful.
善良  性感  幽默
And kind and sexy and funny
绝对是你梦中情人的样子
and everything you ever wanted in a woman.
你真这么觉得
You really think so?
没错  你会一发不可收拾地 爱上她  向她敞开心扉
I do, and you'll fall hopelessly in love and give her your heart.
然后她会拿走你的心  残忍地撕成碎片
And she'll take it and grind it into pathetic, little pieces.
但我们到时候会先上床  对吧
But we'll have sex first, right?
真正的美意大餐
That's Eye-talian.
莱纳德不介意你过来吧
So, um, was Leonard okay with you coming over?
不介意
Oh, yes.
其实他说了  "我没事  我不在乎"
In fact, he said, "I'm fine. I don't care."
而且他的语气绝对不会
And he in no way said it in a manner
让人觉得他在掩饰心中的
which would lead one to believe that he was covering up
痛苦与背叛
feelings of anguish and betrayal.
-很好嘛  -我还要
- Well, good.  - I'm also
很高兴地告诉你他曾为你大声痛哭
pleased to report that he's all cried out over you.
他哭过
He's been crying?
我又漏说了一件
Oh, I believe that was something else
不该跟你提起的事
I wasn't supposed to mention.
哦  天哪  我好难过
Oh, God, I feel terrible.
你也胃疼吗
Do you have a stomachache, too?
没有啊  怎么了  你胃疼吗
No. Why, do you?
不疼
No.
那你为啥问我是不是也胃疼
Why did you ask if I had one, too?
就是吃饭的时候随便聊聊
Just making polite dinner conversation.
该你说了
Your turn.
好吧
All right.
那你最近有啥新鲜事儿吗
So, what's new in your life?
我的新鞋不适合跑步
Well, my new shoes are not made for running.
你去跑步了
Have you been running?
没有
No.
这只是我的怀疑
It's just a suspicion I have.
-我很高兴你这么喜欢我的手艺  -没错
- I'm so glad you like it.  -I do.
莱纳德从来没给我做过饭
Leonard never cooks for me.
估计是因为莱纳德不会做饭吧
Well, maybe that's 'cause Leonard can't cook.
你也不会做饭  但是你为我做了这些
You can't cook and you made me this.
随便啦
Whatever.
对了  还有芝士蛋糕在冰箱里
Ooh, I'm gonna get the cheesecake out of the fridge.
天  我要下犹太人的地狱了[胃酸倒流]
Oh, Lord, I'm in Jewish hell.
你看这个
Look at this.
你觉得她这动作是真的呢
Do you think she's really doing that
还是PS出来的
or is it PhotoShop?
我很确定玛莎·斯图尔特绝对不会光着身子
I'm pretty sure Martha Stewart never got naked
（著名女企业家  曾因经济犯罪入狱）
和一屋子的日本大胖子呆在一起
with a room full of big, fat Japanese guys.
你又不知道
You don't know that.
监狱能改变一个人的
Prison changes people.
你刚去哪儿了
Hey, where you been?
跟你说了嘛  散步啊
I told you, walking.
你散了一个半小时的步
For an hour and a half?
我迷路了
I got lost.
你怎么会迷路的  你的手机上有GPS啊
How could you get lost? Your phone has GPS.
卫星出故障了  有太阳风暴
Satellites are down. Solar flares.
这会儿没有太阳风暴
There are no solar flares right now.
不对  有的
Yes, there are.
老兄  我是搞天体物理的
Dude, I'm an astrophysicist.
要是有太阳风暴的话  我绝对会知道
If there were solar flares, I'd be all up in it.
抱歉  我说错了
I'm sorry. I misspoke.
我刚才其实想说我手机没电了
What I meant to say was my battery died.
他到底是怎么回事啊
What the hell was that about?
不知道
I don't know.
你觉得这真的是希拉里·克林顿在和欧普拉嘿咻吗
Do you think this is really Hillary Clinton doing it with Oprah?
哦  我们真得给你找个小妞了
Oh, we really need to get you a girl.
莱纳德
Leonard.
滚进来吧
Oh, just come in!
谢谢你这么痛快地让我进来了
Thanks for seeing me on such short notice.
你想干嘛  谢尔顿
What do you want, Sheldon?
可能现在不是时候
Maybe this isn't a good time.
快说你干嘛吵醒我  不然我对天发誓我会杀了你
Tell me why you woke me up or I swear to God I will kill you.
你真觉得用死亡威胁我
Do you really think death threats
是展开谈话的恰当方式吗
are an appropriate way to begin this conversation?
有时候  你的社交能力少得简直让我震惊
Sometimes your lack of social skills astonishes me.
你到底想干嘛
What do you want?
你最好先坐下
You may want to sit down.
我正躺着呢
I'm in bed!
了解
Point taken.
你最好先坐起来
You may want to sit up.
谢尔顿
Sheldon!
我一直在背着你见佩妮
I've been seeing Penny behind your back.
好吧
Okay...
你说你"见佩妮"  到底什么意思
When you say "seeing Penny," what exactly does that mean?
我们昨晚一起吃晚餐了
We had dinner last night.
她给我做了意粉加热狗丁
She made me spaghetti with little hot dogs cut up in it.
虽然热狗丁很少
Well, little hot dog.
因为还有五根热狗我都给那条真的狗狗吃了
I gave up the other five hot dogs to a real dog.
很大只的真的狗狗
A real, big dog.
是条该死的猎狗
A hell hound.
我好像离题太远了
Tangential to the primary story.
等下再绕回来说如何
How about I circle back to it?
好
Fine.
你为什么要跟佩妮一起晚餐
Why did you have dinner with Penny?
我说过了  她做了意粉加热狗丁
I told you, she made spaghetti with little hot dogs.
我喜欢吃意粉加热狗丁
I like spaghetti with little hot dogs.
那你为什么还跟我们一起吃中餐
Then why did you have Chinese food with us?
我是怕你不高兴
I didn't want to upset you.
霍华德说得很清楚  我应该先效忠于
Howard made it very clear that my allegiance should be
男同志  而不是为钱卖身的女人们
to male comrades before women who sell their bodies for money.
莫非他说的是  兄弟比妓女重要
Is it possible he said, "Bros before hos"?
对  我改了下措辞  避免提到妓女这个词
Yes, but I rephrased it to avoid offending the hos.
谢尔顿  你跟佩妮做不做朋友我都无所谓
Sheldon, I don't care if you want to be friends with Penny.
这么说  一直困扰我让我噩梦连连的
Oh. Well, so the emotional turmoil that's been keeping me
这种情绪波动  真的是完全不应该啊
from achieving REM sleep was entirely unjustified?
没错
Yes.
要是我奶奶肯定会说
Well... then as my meemaw would say,
我们在这宰猪待客  可居然没人想吃培根[都不领情]
"Looks like we butchered a pig, but nobody wanted bacon."
我想是的
I guess not.
现在  之前我承诺过的  那个题外话
And now, as promised, the tangent.
谢尔顿大战猎狗记
Sheldon and the Hell Hound.
或者说"谁动了我的热狗"
Or How I Lost My Hot Dogs.
我还是回头再来吧
I, I can come back.
别傻了
D-don't be silly.
我们是邻居
We're neighbors.
抬头不见低头见
We're going to run into each other.
还是早点习惯的好
May as well get used to it.
嗯  你说得对
Yeah, I guess you're right.
你习惯了吗
You used to it yet?
-还没  -我也是
- Nope. - Me neither.
谢尔顿好像认为他跟你出去
Oh, Sheldon seemed to think that I would be upset
我会不高兴
about you hanging out with him.
我只是告诉你  没事的
But I just want you to know it's fine.
太好了  因为他妈妈打电话给我了
Oh, oh, good, because, um, his mother called me.
他妈妈
His mother?
对  她想让我带他出去买床单和毛巾
Yeah, she wants me to take him shopping for sheets and towels.
我本来打算带他去的
I was going to do that.
是吗  那还是你带吧
Oh, well, then you... you do it.
不  我根本就不想带  还是你来吧
No, I don't want to do it. You can do it.
好  那你可以带他去买鞋
Okay, you can take him for shoes.
我刚带他去买过鞋
I just took him for shoes.
我只知道他说那鞋子挤脚
Well, all I know is he says they hurt his feet.
好吧  下周六我会带他去买鞋
Fine. I'll take him for shoes next Saturday.
不行不行  我们一帮同事
Oh, no, no, no-- a bunch of us from work
下周六要去迪斯尼乐园
are going to Disneyland next Saturday
谢尔顿也想一起去
and Sheldon wants to come.
你们要带他去迪斯尼乐园
You're taking him to Disneyland?
我讲电话订计划的时候他正好听到
Well, he heard me making plans on the phone.
那我还能拒绝吗
Was I going to say "no"?
好吧
All right.
你们让他塞一堆垃圾食品前  记得先跟我说下
But let me know if you're going to stuff him with junk food.
我可不想帮他打包回一顿美餐 结果只能浪费掉
I don't want to bring home a nice dinner for him and see it go to waste.
我们是去迪斯尼乐园玩
We're going to Disneyland.
他肯定会吃垃圾食品
He's going to eat junk food.
我只是说  事先跟我打个招呼
All I'm saying is give me a heads-up.
好吧  随便吧
Okay, whatever.
还有别让他吃饱了再去玩太空山
And don't let him go on Space Mountain after he eats.
他会说没问题  但我敢肯定
He'll say he can handle it, but I promise
他绝对会把油条都吐你鞋子上
you'll end up with churro puke on your shoes.
好的  明白  还有什么提醒的吗
All right, got it. Is there anything else?
有  别让他靠近高飞狗
Yeah, don't let Goofy near him.
他会噩梦连连  到时候还得我处理
He'll have nightmares and I'll have to deal with it.
高飞狗有什么问题
What's the problem with Goofy?
我也想知道  不过让他靠近布鲁托没事
Wish I knew. He's fine with Pluto.
你觉得《超人总动员》里那个弹力女超人
Hey, do you think the elastic woman in The Incredibles
需要用避孕套吗  还是她自己就能变成套子
needs to use birth control or can she just be a diaphragm?
就这样吧
Well, that's it.
能聊的话题正式都谈完了
We're officially out of things to talk about.
我们回来了
We're home.
都晚上十点了  你们去哪了
It's 10:00.Where have you been?
我们留在那看加州冒险乐园的喷泉秀
We stayed for the California Adventure water show.
纯粹因为迪斯尼魔力太大
It was pure Disney magic.
我准备跟他一起去看的
I was going to see that with him.
那我怎么知道
How was I supposed to know that?
没事的  我会跟你一起再去看一遍的
It's all right. I'll see it again with you.
我还帮他带了吃的  你说过你会先打电话的
And I have food here. You said you were going to call.
我知道是我不好
I know, I know.
我还吃得下
I can still eat.
不行  你已经吐过一次了
No, you already threw up once.
去换上睡衣刷牙
Go put on your PJs and brush your teeth.
好吧  但你们俩别吵架
Okay, but just don't fight
-我们没在吵架  -快去
- We're not fighting. - Just go.
你不谢谢佩妮带你去迪斯尼乐园玩吗
Aren't you going to thank Penny for taking you to Disneyland?
谢谢你  佩妮
Thank you, Penny.
不客气  亲爱的
You're welcome, sweetie.
想来杯咖啡吗
Want a cup of coffee?
我还是先走吧
Oh, um, I should probably get going.
好了  就一杯咖啡而已
Come on. It's just a cup of coffee.
我也觉得这整件事有点扭曲
Uh, yeah, the whole thing seems a little twisted to me, too.
这是什么气味
What am I smelling?
谢尔顿吐在我鞋子上的油条
Sheldon's churro on my shoes.
他睡着的时候  看着真像天使
He's such an angel when he's asleep.
是啊
Yeah.
可惜他还会醒来
Shame he has to wake up.
我觉得我们能做到的
I think we can do it.
趁谢尔顿睡着时闷死他  那不合适吧
Smother Sheldon in his sleep?Wouldn't that be wrong?
不  你跟我  做朋友
No, be friends. You and me.
当然
Oh. Sure.
绝对没问题
Absolutely.
很好  我很开心
Good. I'm glad.
我有个主意  我就随便说说
Here's an idea. I'm just throwing it out there:
当炮友如何
friends who have sex.
晚安  莱纳德
Good night, Leonard.
我开玩笑的
Kidding.
只是朋友间玩笑打混而已
Just a couple of friends Goofing around.
不  高飞狗  别
No, Goofy, no.